Woodbury Shortridge

HUMAN-COMPUTER INTERACTION ENGINEER

1530 Beacon St. Apt. 406, Brookline, MA, 02446

□ (678) 925 7344 | whshortridge@gmail.com | woodburyshortridge.github.io | woodburyshortridge

Summary_

I research, design, prototype, and develop technology-based experiences. I am fascinated by human interaction with technology with a special appreciation for multi-sensory experiences. I am dedicated to shaping emerging technologies with the end-user in mind, and have expertise working with users of varied abilities and in complex task environments. My work spans the fields of human-computer interaction, software engineering, user experience & interface design, and accessibility.

Education

Tufts School of Engineering

Medford, Massachusetts

HUMAN-COMPUTER INTERACTION, CERT

Aug. 2017 - Exp. May. 2019

HCI Certificate program, focusing on the study of new interaction styles, user interface software, display design and perception.

- Coursework: Human-machine system design, Computer Interface Design, Object-oriented programming for Interfaces, Human-computer Interface
- · Advisor: Daniel Hannon, Ph.D

Georgia Institute of Technology

Atlanta, Georgia

B.S. IN PSYCHOLOGY, WITH HONOR

Aug. 2009 - May. 2016

B.S. Psychology with Honor, giving special attention to sensation & perception, human-computer interaction, and cognitive psychology.

- Coursework: Research methods, Human-factors, Cognitive psychology, Sensation & perception, Music technology, Python for multimedia, Engineering Psychology
- Thesis: Auditory and Head-Up Displays for Eco-Driving Interfaces
- Advisor: Bruce Walker, Ph.D.

Experience_

The Institute for Human Centered Design

Boston, Massachusetts

LEAD HUMAN-COMPUTER INTERACTION ENGINEER

Aug. 2016 - Present

Lead a broad range of consulting and educational projects with a mission to develop accessible and inclusive technology. Responsibilities include contextual inquiry research with an emphasis on multisensory experience, prototyping, front-end development, and user-centered design. Select projects:

- National Endowment for the Arts | User-centered web app design and development
- ADA National Network | Web accessibility prototyping, user-testing, and development
- Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority | Inclusive UI design guidance for transit web apps
- · Smithsonian Institution | Inclusive touch interactives, digital immersions, and way-finding tools

Georgia Institute of Technology

Atlanta, Georgia

RESEARCH ASSISTANT, SONIFICATION LAB

Dec. 2014 - Aug. 2016

Worked with multiple interdisciplinary research teams developing multimodal interfaces displaying information for complex task environments. Select projects:

- Conducted participatory design studies and development of auditory and head-up in-vehicle interfaces to allow safer completion of secondary tasks (ICAD'2017)
- Research-driven development of a weather app with a talk-back UI and created earcons that provide the 'glanceable' function of visual weather icons to screen reader dependent users (MobileHCl'2016)
- Assisted research and development of interfaces displaying reliability and confidence for autonomous vehicles (Automotive UI'17)

Publications

Auditory and Head-Up Displays for Eco-Driving Interfaces

Pennsylvania, PA

THE 23RD INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON AUDITORY DISPLAY Shortridge, W., Gable, T. M., Noah, B. E., & Walker, B. N.

Jun. 2017

Talkin'about the weather:

Incorporating TalkBack functionality and sonifications for accessible app design

Florence, Italy

THE 18TH INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON HUMAN-COMPUTER INTERACTION WITH MOBILE DEVICES AND SERVICES

Sept. 2016

Tomlinson, B. J., Schuett, J. H., Shortridge, W., Chandran, J., & Walker, B. N.

DECEMBER 1, 2018 WOODBURY SHORTRIDGE · CV

Invited Talks

2018	HubWeek , Inclusive Design + Innovation Immersion	Boston, MA
2018	American Alliance of Museums, Multi-Sensory Technologies for Inclusion in Museum Exhibits	Phoenix, AZ
2018	Smithsonian Institution, Design for Accessible Digital Surfaces	Washington, DC
2017	American Alliance of Museums, Multi-sensory Technology for Accessibility & Inclusion	St. Louis, MO

Competitions.

Microsoft's Machine Learning for Accessibility

Cambridge, MA

PARTNERS: KALLI RETZEPI, DANIEL LEVINE, AND JUDY SHEN

Jun. 2018

Re-imagined the web-browsing experience with a voice and tangible interface, and leveraging natural language processing to deliver text-summarisation with an easy to navigate, interactive semantic mapping of contents

Tufts University Sonos Design Challenge

Boston, MA

PARTNER: ALI DECKER

Oct. 2017

Winning project: A design exploration into human-Al collaboration, built a mobile app that curates a music play-list based on user supplied photos

Mentorship _____

2018	Tufts University Senior Capstone Sponsor, Inclusive design for the visually impaired	IHCD, Boston, MA
2018	Internship Supervisor, Dorothy Qu Designer, Dartmouth College	IHCD, Boston, MA
2018	Internship Supervisor, Shuangxing Liu Engineer, Nanyang Technological University	IHCD, Boston, MA

Skills_

Design Ableton, Adobe Suite, Sketch

Machine Learning dLib, Keras, OpenCV, Tensorflow

Programming C++, Java, Python

Prototyping Arduino, inVision, MaxMSP, Raspberry Pi, Proto.io

Methods Biometrics, Contextual inquiry, Personas/scenarios, Usability testing, Storyboarding

Web Technologies AWS, GraphQL, JavaScript, Node.js, PHP, React.js, SASS, SQL

Statistics SPSS, R

Professional Service _____

UXPA Boston Volunteer **Boston CHI** Member